Farming Life in Another World
Masshiro hikari no naka me o samashite
hajimatteiku sutoorii
Fumidasu atarashii sekai donna hana o sakaseyou?
Kumori sora datte mizutamari de yogoretatte
Bokura wa susumu
Souzou mo shinai mirai ga matteiru kitto
Deatte deatte tsunagatteku
Waraeba mawari mo egao ni naru
Chiisana tane maite sodateyou
Yagate ookina hana ni naru
Koukai ya shippai wa kate ni shite
Karafuru na shiawase de afureru youni
Bokura te o toriatte wakeatte
Sekaijuu ni hirogatteike Flower Ring
Spring passed us by, and the sun began
shining down stronger each day.
The vegetables all look
so much brighter and more colorful
after they've been sunbathing for a while.
Hey, everyone!
It's break time. Let's have lunch.
Yay!
Okay!
Let's go!
I'm starving!
I'll get everything ready.
Thanks.
This one might grow too tall like this.
I feel like I'm much more knowledgeable about
this stuff than when I first started farming.
Let's see about the other plants...
Darling!
Huh...
Lu?
Come on, it's break time.
You need to take breaks too, you know?
When I look out at the crops,
I just can't help myself.
Magic really is great.
I've told you; this is basic stuff.
I feel revitalized.
If you work too hard,
you could collapse.
I think I'll be fine.
More importantly, is it okay for you
to be walking around?
Yeah, I'm okay now.
In fact, I've heard it's good to
get some exercise now.
Is that right?
Everyone's been teaching me
all kinds of stuff.
Obviously, you can't push yourself too hard,
but I heard from the girls in the village
Reproduction and prosperity!
that it's important to exercise
to keep your body strong.
I found out that a few of the ogre maid girls
have actually given birth themselves.
That's reassuring.
Yeah.
Unfortunately, I don't really know
anything about that stuff.
It strange to think that she
has a child inside her belly.
I wonder what that must feel like for her.
So, what it's actually feel like?
Now that you've gotten so big,
it's got to feel heavy.
Yeah, I think it's about the same
as two heads of cabbage.
That means...
you must feel pretty heavy.
How lovely. I'm so jealous.
I wonder if it'll be a boy.
Or maybe a girl?
Is there any way to know that now?
Can we do anything to
make you more comfortable?
Please let us know if there's
anything we can do to help.
Everyone's being so kind and
helpful that I'm fine for now.
My appetite is back now, too.
The only thing bothering me is...
that I can't drink any alcohol.
Mayor!
Forgive our insolence,
but we've come to make a request today.
What is it, everyone?
We're here to ask that Tia and
everyone else's resolution not go to waste!
They've all become so dejected
that we can't bear to watch.
We implore you!
Please sell off all the alcohol in the village!
Huh?
I see. You're all giving up alcohol for Lu.
That's right, however...
When we think about
not being able to drink, we just...
Whenever we're eating and we think
"Man, some alcohol would
go great with this!" it feels like...
Just like that.
It's that bad?
At this point I believe the only option is
to remove the source of their suffering.
Calm down.
I'm happy that you're all doing this,
but I think you'll end up regretting it
if we sell all the alcohol.
Besides, alcohol isn't something
we can quickly make again.
Just think of it this way.
The taste of alcohol changes
the longer you let it age after making it.
I'm sure that if you can hold out for now,
it'll taste even better later.
Let's all tough it out
while looking forward to that.
Mayor, can you tell us
if we've done something wrong?
What happened?
Even though everyone used to
love drinking alcohol,
none of them will drink
a single drop now.
Ah.
Really? So that's all it was!
So it's not like they stopped
enjoying the alcohol we produce.
Of course not!
I'm sorry. We should have
let you know right away.
I was thinking that we should
slow down production right away.
But now I think we should do the opposite.
Yeah. I'm sure everyone will
drink more to make up for lost time.
Great! We'll do our best to live up to
everyone's expectations!
Are you feeling okay?
I'm fine.
I'm not in here because
I'm not feeling well.
The sun is really strong today
so I'm staying inside just to be safe.
But it's almost time, isn't it?
It looks that way.
If I get any bigger than this,
I really won't be able to move at all.
Where'd you get that?
Tia and the angels came to visit me
and brought it with them.
They said they found it blooming on a
far away mountain where there was still snow.
It's really pretty.
It kind of makes the room feel cooler.
Believe it or not, that flower
is actually releasing cold air.
Excuse me!
This is a secret mountain elf medicine
that's said to bring about
good health and vigor.
Please take it!
This is really valuable, isn't it?
I'd rather it be used
when the time is right
than have it sit around
in storage forever.
It sounds like she's talking about
a rare item from a game.
Hi, Lu!
This is a gem that's supposed to help
with magic recovery!
I found it in my father's treasure room!
After much hard work and toiling,
it's finally complete.
I made pudding.
Here!
It's a good luck charm wreath!
Are you okay?
Do you want me to peel apples for you?
You must be very hungry now, right?
I made tomato and tofu miso soup!
Tomato?
It's surprisingly good.
Isn't it?!
We're all born from eggs,
so I have absolutely no idea
what I can do now to help out.
But at the very least...
I can offer you my blood to drink
so that you'll grow stronger!
I don't think my teeth can
make it through that.
I'm really happy.
Me too.
What's this?
A wooden mallet?
It's from Donovan.
He said to trust him that it would
come in handy later.
Come in handy?
Do you need a wooden mallet for childbirth?
What's wrong?
My belly feels kind of...
Does that mean...
I think so.
Bring the towels here.
Boil more water.
When the time came, I found myself
in a panic for a little while.
But now there's nothing left
that I can do to help out.
The two moons...
On my first night here, I watched them
from this very same place.
Back then I was alone.
I wanted to live somewhere by myself,
away from anyone else.
But now, I have everyone here.
That's why I'm sure that...
After that, time passed by
like a blur until morning.
Actually, it's more accurate to say
that I don't have any memories of
what happened after that.
Everything went great.
They're both doing well.
Come hold him.
Can I?
Um...
Be careful.
He was just born. Watch his neck.
Make sure to support it with your arm.
Yeah.
He's warm.
And he's heavier than I expected.
Even though he's so small.
He moved!
Of course he does.
He was moving around a lot
when he was still in my belly.
I see.
He smiled!
That was a smile, right?
He's happy that his dad's holding him.
That's right.
I've really become a father.
Back in my original world,
I was suffering from an illness.
I hope he never has to go through that.
Grow up to be strong for me.
He's not going to just grow up strong,
we're going to raise him to be strong.
Together.
That's right.
What's wrong? What should I do?!
Please calm down!
Just relax.
Done!
It's been a week since Lu gave birth.
My son's name is Alfred.
That was Lu's idea.
I guess his race is technically
half-vampire... maybe?
But right now he looks like
a normal human.
This is where I started living by myself.
A lot more people live here now.
There are more buildings now, too.
Everything kept growing.
Now it's a village where I live
together with everyone.
Then one day, I became mayor.
And now, I've finally become a father.
Speaking of which...
I need to do something to thank
all the villagers for their kindness.
They've all been working so hard
up until now to help build up the village.
What did you gather us
to talk about today?
The thing is, I've been thinking about
a new system I want to
set up for this village.
A system?
Yeah.
This.
It's a reward medal.
A medal?
What is it for?
I want to give these medals out
to everyone who helped
build up the village as thanks
for their hard work.
How do we use them?
You can trade them for goods you want
or use them to get
other things you're after.
Then they're like money, right?
Yeah.
I figured that one day The Great Tree Village
would need its own currency.
Right now we have
a lot of stuff in the village.
Crops, hunted game meat, and traded goods.
As the mayor of the village, I've been
taking charge of all these things
and then distributing them
to everyone myself.
Whenever someone wants something,
they come ask me about it.
But with the increasing
population of the village,
handling all of these transactions on my own
has become borderline impossible.
I see.
If we're going to handle transactions
on our own, then we need currency.
That's right.
Can't we just trade goods with each other?
Think about it this way.
How many strawberries is
a single apple worth?
Um, I'd say about three strawberries.
I'd say they're one to one
since I prefer strawberries.
Yup. Everyone places
a different value for things.
That's why I want to use currency
for our transactions.
So that's what money is for.
How many barrels of gold
is an apple worth?
I almost never use money so I'm not sure.
You count it in barrels?
I expect nothing less from the dragons.
Anyways, I think it would
cause a lot of turmoil
if I switched everything over
to currency right away.
So for now I'm going to start by
giving these out as reward medals.
That's the plan.
I see. In that case,
let's try them out for a while.
Great.
For now, let's just think of these as
convenient little vouchers
you exchange for things.
And so to get things going, I started by
giving all the villagers three medals each.
I couldn't give out medals to
all of Kuro and Zabuton's families,
so I gave them 30 medals each.
On top of that, I have to make them all by hand
in a way that they can't be counterfeited.
That limits how many I can make.
Everyone reacted differently.
Give me wine.
Some people traded them
for wine right away.
for furniture and the like.
Some people traded them for weapons
that Dryme had brought us as gifts.
And some people...
just decorated their rooms with them.
I'd prefer it if they didn't just
hold onto them without spending any.
That's how I started
introducing the reward medals
that were the precursors for currency, but...
Let's see.
Oh! I've got it.
...it resulted in orders for
custom made furniture and toys
to become incredibly popular.
If anything, I feel like
I'm doing more work now.
Uh, just wait a little while for me.
In addition, I said that I wanted to use these
as a guide for how much things are worth.
But sometimes it's hard to determine exactly
how much a single medal should be worth.
Mayor!
I want you to give me... a baby!
Is that an option?!
It's not!
What if I give you three?
That's not the issue here.
In the end, we settled on them
renting out the mayor for a day instead.
And a little while after that...
...it was finally time for the big feast
to celebrate the birth of my son.
Cheers!
I kind of feel bad.
I kept them all waiting for a while.
Yeah, we couldn't have a feast
right after you gave birth.
Well, they all seem to be enjoying
themselves now, so I think it's okay.
I am a little worried that they
might drink too much, though.
Hi there! It's your big sister, Flora!
By the way, is that...
Yeah.
Donovan told me to
bring it here with me today.
Sorry we took so long.
What's this?
It's a special new kind of wine
that we made just for you guys.
This is our way of celebrating with you,
so make sure you do it right!
It's time to use it!
You mean this?
I see. So that's what it's for.
Here we go!
Congratulations, Mayor!
That felt really good.
Yeah, it did.
I never thought I'd be cracking open
a barrel of wine in celebration in this world.
I guess doing something big like this always
makes celebrations more fun, wherever you are.
Hey everyone, drink up!
Man, this booze is great!
The food is great! Congratulations!
Now it's time for my secret technique!
Is she okay?
Well, what do you think of the wine?
Donovan...
The thing is...
Ah, I get it.
I'm sorry, but I've been told I shouldn't
drink as long as I'm breastfeeding.
I see. You can't drink
as long as he's still a baby.
I get it.
Right now, I'll let them all drink for me.
I'll enjoy the wine by watching
all their smiling faces.
I've got an idea.
How about before everyone drinks it all,
we bottle it so we can age the wine?
Oh, that sounds great!
We can hold onto it until Alfred
is old enough to drink it himself.
Great idea!
Alright!
I'll make sure to keep it safe
and age it so it's the best wine ever!
Get started on this right away!
If we drag our feet, they'll drink it all.
I want more!
The day I can drink wine
with my son. I can't wait.
That day will be here before you know it
as long as you're enjoying life
every day like this.
Look!
Alfred loves his big sister Flora so much!
I think he wants to be my baby!
Stop right there.
About The Great Tree Village...
What is it this time?!
They had a child.
It was a healthy baby boy.
Oh, that's nice.
Based on all of the information
we've heard so far,
I think the very notion that we could
challenge them is impossible as of now.
So you've finally realized it?
We should be thinking about
how we can maintain an amicable
relationship with that village.
If we can marry off someone from the
Demonic Kingdom to their village one day,
then it will guarantee our safety here!
Unacceptable.
Pardon?
I won't hand over Yuri as a bride!
Not to anyone ever!
No matter what!
Please calm down.
Did you gather all the goods?
Yes.
It'll leave a poor impression if we don't
make sure to congratulate them properly.
We must make sure
all our preparations are perfect.
I want our relationship with that village
to continue on for a long time.
Is something the matter?
No, it's nothing.
I just had a dream
for the first time in a while.
Could it be...
that you have a hangover?
But you didn't drink last night, either.
No. I'm fine now.
In that case, I want to talk about
something that Granmaria and the others
brought up with me.
People that want to move here?
Yes.
They were living in a different forest,
and now they're looking for
somewhere new to live.
Dryme said that he's got some people that were
driven out of their homes because of a war.
My father also mentioned that
there are some refugees
that need a place to stay because of
the war with Fullhardt Kingdom.
How many are there?
It's not an exact figure, but...
Um, let's see...
If I'm giving a rough estimate, it's about...
We broke the three-digit mark.
I think we'd need another village like this one
if we're going to take that many people.
Then let's do it.
Let's build a new village for the people
that want to move here.
That sounds great!
If we do that, then lots of people
can move here.
So it'll be The Great Tree Village 2?
Wait a minute, won't that be a ton of work?
We need to prepare and gather supplies.
We'll do our best!
This village saved us all.
If someone needs our help,
we can't just leave them alone.
Still, we'll need to plan everything out
very carefully for this.
Where should we build it?
Alright. Let's have a meeting
about it right away.
I'm counting on your help, everyone.
Yeah!
Kisetsu no kaze fuwari yubisaki de sotto kanjiru
Sora ni ukabu kumo ni daisuki sagasou
Tokei no hari wa ima wa wasure
Shinkokyuu hitotsu shitemiyouyo
Nanairo no keshiki kokoro hibiku
Donna negai koto demo kanau ki ga suru
Kimi ga soba ni iru nara
Yume mitaina hibi o kuretan dayo
Atatakakute yasashii basho de
Itsumademo egao o miseteite